

# Matt Hogeboom INTERACTIVE DESIGNER

mobile email website 1 (949) 542-9693 matthewhogeboom@gmail.com

#### Introduction

My name is Matt, I am a Designer currently living in Laguna Niguel CA. I have 18 years of experience designing and building websites and interactive applications. The past year has been spent working on a freelance basis, and before that I spent 9 years on an award-winning team of developers at Newsday.com. I design and build responsive websites and interactive applications. I have experience working on a variety of interactive platforms for desktop, mobile and television display. I have worked in a variety of different environments from large corporations to small boutique advertising agencies. I have excelled at delivering robust website projects under strict deadlines. I enjoy the pace and energy of a creative work environment and enjoy collaborating with co-workers and clients.

### **Expertise**

- Web Development
- · UX & UI Design
- Mobile App Design
- HTML5

- · CSS/SASS
- ¡Query
- Wordpress Development
- Brand Development

- Search Engine Optimization
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Hosting & Maintenance
- Site Troubleshooting

## **Professional Experience**

#### Freelance Web Designer

Web Developer

2018 - Present

Branding, Logo Design and Website Development. Leverage Wordpress and custom HTML/CSS for client web solutions. SEO and enhancing and upgrading existing systems.

#### Newsday LLC

Senior Designer

September 2008 - December 2017

Worked with award-winning team of developers on web projects as well as mobile apps. Designed and developed web and mobile applications, managed projects and coordinated with department teams to deliver projects accurately and on schedule. Managed third-party applications, site troubleshooting and ensuring cross browser compatibility for high-traffic news industry.

#### Zero Gravity

Web Designer

December 2007 - August 2008

Designed and managed projects from concept through completion. Managed Flash enhanced websites. Designed and developed dynamic websites using HTML, CSS, AJAX, jQuery and PHP. Coordinated with clients on web content and website management with MODX.

#### LKGS Interactive

Senior Designer

May 2004 - September 2007

Brand development. Logo, print and website design. Dynamic data-driven website development and email campaigns using HTML, PHP and FLASH. Created and managed web projects with remote staff from conception through completion.

#### Education

Hendricks Institute of Technology Interactive Design Certification 1999-2000 Stony Brook University Undergrad EGL 1996 - 1998 Suffolk County Community College Associates Degree 1994 - 1996